# Oliver Bell

#### github.com/freshollie • ollie.codes

A British computer programmer with 3 years of industry experience and a First Class BSc (Hons) in Computer Science. Specialises in full-stack software engineering. Expertise in designing and writing, tested, maintainable, and distributed software in many languages.

# **Employment**

## YOOX Net-a-Porter Group, London, UK

**Software Engineer** (May 2019 - Present)

- Working on a team developing internal apps with full-stack JavaScript/TypeScript
- Specialising in writing functional React, using styled-components, GraphQL for local state and network, and graphql-codegen to enforce types between front and backend.
- Following TDD using react-testing-library and jest, with BDD end to end tests
- Pushed for and implemented a monorepo based architecture for the team

# **Alelion Energy Systems GmbH,** Munich, Germany **Software Engineer** (August 2017 - September 2018)

- Developed HA software for their distributed energy storage platform
- Worked with Docker, Python, TypeScript, C++, and Java
- Wrote their main time-series API which used Scylla (cassandra) for a data backend
- Designed and wrote an orchestrator for dynamic service deployment to a docker swarm
- Worked as lead in a small team to re-write their main "Control-Center" UI in Angular 6
- Designed and implemented many microservices to split-up their UI backend

## IndiCater Software LTD, Henley-On-Thames, UK

Intern Software Developer (July 2014 - August 2014) (July 2015 - September 2015)

- Developed web-based software used for the management of back-of-house catering
- Wrote server-side VBscript, and frontend javascript

#### Tech



#### **Interests**

- Programming (since 2012)
- FPV Miniquad Racing
- Reverse engineering
- Free Software
- DevOps
- Skiing
- Film-making
- Electronics

#### **Part-time**

- McDonalds (2013-2017)
- Compass (2016-2017)
- Delaware North (2018-2019)

## **Education**

First class BSc (Hons) Computer Science - Coventry University (2015-2019)

A Levels and GCSEs - Edgbarrow School, Crowthorne (2008-2015)

- Computing A Level (B) & GCSE (A)
- Maths A Level (C) & GCSE (A\*)

## **Projects**

## Betaflight Configurator - github.com/freshollie/fresh-configurator

I am in the process of writing an application to configure drone flight controllers over USB. This required writing; a parser to communicate with the flight controller, an api to decode and encode data for the flight controller, a server to provide the data as a GraphQL interface, and an Electron application written in React. All written with TypeScript for full type coverage. The project is structured as a monorepo, and the generic parts of the application are available on NPM: <a href="mailto:npm.im/org/betaflight">npm.im/org/betaflight</a>

#### ThatTikTok.Video - thattiktok.video/

That Tiktok Video is an online video curation service which allows users to add TikTok videos which they want to be able to search. The site was built in Next.JS with TypeScript and GraphQL, and is designed with SEO optimisation in mind. The app is a work in progress, but I hope to add more features as time goes on. The current state is proof of concept.